AISHWARYA KAMATH

Email: aish@nyu.edu, Github: ashkamath, Website: ashkamath.github.io

RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research interests lie broadly in machine learning and its applications to natural language processing and computer vision. I am particularly interested in using information from multiple sources such as text, images, video and speech to improve commonsense reasoning capabilities of machines.

EDUCATION

New York University

United States

PhD Candidate, Data Science

Sept 2019 - present

- Focus: Natural language processing, multimodal understanding, commonsense reasoning
- Advisors: Professors Yann LeCun and Kyunghyun Cho

University of Massachusetts Amherst

United States

Master of Science, Computer Science - GPA: 3.9/4

Sept 2016 - May 2018

- Focus: Natural language processing; structured prediction using indirect supervision
- Advisor: Professor Andrew McCallum

Manipal Institute of Technology

India

Bachelor of Technology, Electronics and Communication - GPA: 9.16/10

July 2012 - May 2016

WORK EXPERIENCE

Google AI United States

Research Intern June 2021 - August 2021

Student Researcher September 2021 - November 2021

- Mentors: Jason Baldridge, Zarana Parekh and Peter Anderson
- Grounded language understanding for Vision & Language Navigation

Facebook AI Research United States

Research Intern

June 2020 - August 2020

- Mentors: Yann LeCun, Nicolas Carion
- End to end multimodal models for commonsense reasoning

Machine Learning Research Group, Oracle Labs

United States

Machine Learning Engineer, Data Science Team

June 2018 - August 2019

- Building domain specific NLP systems
- Providing machine learning solutions to internal product groups

Machine Learning Research Group, Oracle Labs

United States

Summer Intern, Research Team

June 2017 - September 2017

- Advisors: Jean-Baptiste Tristan and Michael Wick
- Worked on image classification to detect cervical cancer on real-world data obtained from medical clinics in Cameroon

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

New York University, CDS

United States

Teaching Assistant

September 2020 - December 2020

Deep Learning

African Masters in Machine Intelligence (AMMI)

Teaching Assistant

Deep Learning for Natural Language Processing

Senegal (remote) May 2021

PUBLICATIONS

- "MDETR - Modulated Detection for End-to-End Multi-Modal Understanding"

Aishwarya Kamath, Mannat Singh, Yann LeCun, Ishan Misra, Gabriel Synnaeve, Nicolas Carion. International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV) 2021. Selected for oral presentation (top 3% of submitted papers).

- "AdapterFusion: Non-Destructive Task Composition for Transfer Learning"

Jonas Pfeiffer, **Aishwarya Kamath**, Andreas Ruckle, Kyunghyun Cho, Iryna Gurevych. Selected for **oral presentation** at European Chapter of the ACL (EACL) 2021.

- "AdapterHub: A Framework for Adapting Transformers"

Jonas Pfeiffer, Andreas Rckl, Clifton Poth, **Aishwarya Kamath**, Ivan Vulić, Sebastian Ruder, Kyunghyun Cho, Iryna Gurevych.

Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP) 2020: Systems Demonstrations.

- "What do Deep Networks Like to Read?"

Jonas Pfeiffer*, Aishwarya Kamath*, Sebastian Ruder.

Arxiv preprint, September 2019.

- "Specializing Distributional Vectors of All Words for Lexical Entailment"

Aishwarya Kamath*, Jonas Pfeiffer*, Edoardo M. Ponti, Goran Glavas, Ivan Vulić.

Best Paper Award at the Representation Learning for NLP Workshop at ACL 2019.

- "A Survey on Semantic Parsing"

Aishwarya Kamath, Rajarshi Das.

Conference on Automatic Knowledge Base Construction (AKBC) 2019.

- "Training Structured Prediction Energy Networks with Indirect Supervision"

Amirmohammad Rooshenas, Aishwarya Kamath and Andrew McCallum.

Selected for **oral presentation** at NAACL-HLT 2018.

AWARDS

- DeepMind Fellowship 2019-2020
- NYU Center for Data Science Fellowship 2019-2024
- NeurIPS 2019 Travel Award

ACADEMIC SERVICES

- Reviewer for NeurIPS 2019/20, AKBC 2019/21, EACL 2021, ICML 2021
- Program Committee member for EurNLP 2019, DeeLIO 2020/21, RepL4NLP 2021
- Instructor at the NYU AI school 2021

INVITED TALKS

– Intel Deep Learning CoP Talk Series	May 2021
- Google Image-Text group	June 2021
– UKP Lab, TU Darmstadt & CIS Lab Ludwig Maximilian University of Munich	
Joint Invited Talk Series	June 2021
– Microsoft Research Vision-and-Language Summer Research Talk Series	July 2021